准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
上电视
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
别磨蹭  涂鸦先生
Come on, Mr. Doodles
我们时间不多
we haven't got all day
得马上去我最爱的餐厅
We got to down to me favorite restaurant
我的餐厅
Mine
来拍我们第一条蟹堡王广告
where we're shooting
our first ever Krusty Krab commercial
广告播完
After this commercial airs
就能宾客盈门了
we'll be swarming with customers
我都能感觉到自己在流钱汗了
I can already feel myself sweating money
不对  我让章鱼哥来安排拍摄事宜
No, I got Squidward organizing the whole thing
他  怎么说呢
He's, you know
有艺术
artsy
怎么
What the?
蟹堡王
好贵的样子
This looks expensive
让一让
Out of my way
借过一下
Coming through
不滚你们就完蛋了
Move it or lose it
章鱼哥
Squidward
怎么了
What?
这到底是怎么回事
What in Neptune's name is going on?
在拍广告啊  蟹老板
We're making the commercial, Mr. Krabs
你现在就是在乱丢我的钱
What you're doing is throwing away me money
都交代过你只租绝对有必要的东西了
I told you to rent only what's absolutely necessary
场上东西全都有必要
This is all necessary
那这堆没用的垃圾是怎么回事
Well, what's all this useless junk?
是第28幕要用的没用垃圾
That's the useless junk for scene 28
那你要怎么解释那玩意
Oh, well, how do you explain that?
第二家蟹堡王
A second Krusty Krab?
蟹堡王  大家都得有替补演员
Mr. Krabs, everyone needs an understudy
这倒是
Well, you got me there
可要他来干什么
But why do we need him?
拍广告压力非常大  蟹老板
This job gets very stressful, Mr. Krabs
好了  全都给我滚
All right, get lost, all of you
开除你们
You're fired
快走
Go on
滚
Scram
马上给我滚  死骗子
Get out of here, you moochers
没错  快滚
That's right, keep moving
除了你
Except you
你留下
You stay
真是太棒了
Well, this is just great
这下拍摄团队一个都不剩了
Now we've got no crew to make the commercial
胡说八道什么啊  章鱼哥
What are you talking about, Squidward?
全世界最便宜的拍摄团队就在这里
We got the cheapest crew in the world
你  我
You, me
还有海绵宝宝
and Spongebob
说到他  那小东西哪去了
Speaking of which, where is that little barnacle?
我在这  老板
I'm down here, sir
你在干什么  小子
What are you doing, lad?
章鱼哥说活埋自己能协助拍摄
Squidward said I could help by burying myself
别闹了  快出来
Quit fooling and come on out
我需要你来当广告演员
I need you to be in the commercial
我
Me?
当蟹堡王广告演员
In the Krusty Krab commercial?
我
Me?
但
But-
别扯淡了  章鱼哥先生
Don't throw your buts at me, Mr. Squidward
时间很紧
We got a timetable to keep
广告今晚就放
This thing airs tonight
今晚
Tonight?
没错
Yep
我特地买了个黄金时段的广告位
I got a sweet deal on a prime-time slot
凌晨三点二十八分
就快开播了  小蜗
It's almost on, Gary
没错  我也很兴奋
Yeah, I got butterflies, too
史上史上最兴奋的事马上就要来了
This is the most exciting thing
to ever happen in the history of history
小蜗快看  开播了
Look, Gary, it's on
小珍  我出了个很严重的问题
Oh, Jen, I've got a real problem
什么问题呢  艾米
What's your problem, Amy?
我手上有这么多钱
I've got all this money
不知道要怎么花
and I don't know what to do with it
而且我还饿坏了
and I'm hungry
谁在那
Who's there?
哪来的声音
Where's that coming from?
万岁
Yippee
是蟹老板
It's Mr. Krabs
没错  艾米
That's right, Amy
你的小问题我都听到了
I heard all about your little problem
我是来帮你解决的
and I'm here to help
跟我来
Follow me
这是哪里
Where are we?
这个地方正是
Why, we're at none other than
蟹堡王
The Krusty Krab
你是不是说了
Did you say
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab?
没错
That's right
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab
诞生了举世闻名的
Home of the world famous
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patty
什么是蟹黄堡
What's a Krabby Patty?
七大洋里最美味的食物非它莫属
Why, it's only the most mouth-watering
appetizing food in the seven seas
我在那边  小蜗
There I am, Gary
我在那边
There I am
先从新鲜的肉饼开始
We start with a fresh patty
香烤多汁
grilled and juicy
加上酥脆的海底蔬菜与奶酪
Add some crisp undersea veggies and cheese
最后再配上神秘酱料  以及面包
Topped off with secret sauce and some buns
看好了
Voila
蟹黄堡
A Krabby Patty
我想来个蟹黄堡
I want a Krabby Patty
我也是
Me, too
蟹黄堡好不好吃  大小姐们
How are you liking them Krabby Patties, girls?
快看小蜗  我又出镜了
Look, Gary, there I am again
快看
Look
又多了两位满意的客人
Two more satisfied customers
大家快来
So, why don't you come on in
今天就给自己买个蟹黄堡吧
and have yourself a Krabby Patty today?
蟹堡王
The Krusty Krab
快过来花钱
Come spend your money here
刚刚是我一生中最棒的60秒
That was the best 60 seconds of my life
该睡觉了
Well, time for bed
现在该去我最爱的地方最我最爱的事
Time to go do my favorite thing at my favorite place
你
Hey, you
早安  老人家
Top of the morning, Oldster
我昨晚看电视看到你了
I saw you on TV last night
麦麸片
全新麦麸片
New Bran Flakes
全新浓厚风味
Bold new taste
麦麸片
Bran Flakes
真的吗
You did?
没错  我看广告看到你的
Yeah, you were on a commercial
还真是
You're right
他居然认得我
He recognized me
对
Yep
再见  麦麸片
See you later, Bran Flakes
那麦片盒真好
What a nice cereal box
你不是上电视的那位吗
"Weren't you that guy on TV?"
对  我就是那位
"Yes, I am that guy
你能注意到我真是不错
How kind of you to notice"
你不是昨晚上电视的那位吗
"Weren't you that guy on the television last night?"
没错  就是我
"Yes, that was me
我
I"
不好意思  先生
Please excuse me, sir
没关系
That's quite all right
你好  我是海绵宝宝
海绵宝宝
"Spongebob"
我声名远扬了
I'm getting recognized all over
然后大家多半就要开始
Next thing you know
people are going to start doing stuff
帮忙开门什么的
like holding doors open for
先生  我不胜荣幸
Why, sir, I'm flattered
是吗
Really?
没闻出你要进的味
I don't smell anything
你走吧  小伙子
You're on your way, kid
不好意思  先生
Excuse me, sir
能给个餐巾纸吗
Could I get a napkin?
那当然了  先生
Why, of course, dear sir
下次有事随时找我
And next time, feel free to approach me
在房间对面问话一定很没面子吧
It must be so degrading to ask from across the room
请问这张纸得给谁呢
And who am I making this bad boy out to?
给我尾鳍
To my tail fin
我自己拿算了
I'll get it myself
鱼老日
F-I-N
写好了  贵人
There we are, darling
看来他太害羞了
Shyness got the best of him
你在这啊  海绵宝宝
There you are, Spongebob
我要你来
I need you to
没问题  章鱼哥
No problem, Squidward
我已经签好名了
I got one already made out
品鉴吧
Enjoy
给我尾鳍
爱你的海绵宝宝
"To my tail fin"
对  我就是上电视的那位
Yes, I am that guy on TV
看啊
Look
上班期间请大家不要拍照
Please, good people, no photos at work
番茄酱在这
Here's the ketchup
调料区
还是拍一张吧
Well, maybe just one
再拍一张
Another one?
好
Okay
林波舞
Limbo
现在是
And now the
有了
I got it
你在这啊  海绵宝宝
There you are, Spongebob
飞行员
Jet pilot
我要你来
Now I need you to
好了  小子
All right, boy
去把厕所擦干净
Get in there and scrub the head
别一直犯老毛病
and stop acting so predictable
怀才不遇啊
So misunderstood
诸位
Alas, good people
即便最明亮的明星也会黯淡
even the brightest of stars grow weary
我亦不例外
And I am no exception
但只需小憩一刻  我将再度闪耀
But I will shine again
after a quick break in my quarters
保持美丽
Stay beautiful
你昨晚有看到葛兰迪麦粉鱼
Were you able to catch Glandy McPinkfish
出演比目鱼侠这部剧吗
on Flounderman last night?
没看  他演得怎么样
No, how was he?
虽然本来就知道他演技好
Well, I knew this guy's acting was good
但头一回发现他唱功特强
but his singing is phenomenal
摆摊的  我跟你说
I'm tell you, Vender
要是他能出个人专辑
if that guy was to cut a solo record
肯定会热销
it would be a hit
个人专辑
Solo record
要是我开除他
So, if I fire him
让接班的工作量翻倍
and make his successor do twice the work
请进
Come in
是你啊  海绵宝宝
It's just you, Spongebob
厕所最好已经擦漂亮了
Those heads better be beautiful
很漂亮  蟹老板
They are, Mr. Krabs
我的脑袋也一样漂亮
and so is mine
现在我要跟你放点话  小螃蟹
And now I got to lay something on you, Krabs baby
唯一要你放的
The only thing you better lay
就是烤架上的肉饼  小厨子
is some patties on the grill, fry boy
那我做不来  蟹老弟
I can't take that gig, Krabber
那段厨师生涯已经结束了
That phase of my career is over
我现在是演员
I'm an entertainer now
你到底在说什么鬼话
What in blazes are you talking about?
蟹老板  先跳出思维定势思考一下
Come on, Krabs, let's think outside the box for a second
广告已经作古了
Commercials are old hat
大众要的是音乐
The people want music
我要能改变命运的话早变了  蟹老弟
If I could change fate, I would, Krabsie
但我内心深处是一位演员
But I'm an entertainer deep down
一位公众人物
a people's person
我们立场一致  对吧
We're on the same page here, aren't we?
蟹黄堡的油烟一定把你熏昏头了
Boy, those krabby fumes must have got to your head
去借章鱼哥的防毒面具
Borrow Squidward's gas mask
借完马上回来工作
then get right back to work
就知道你能理解
I knew you'd understand
感谢你发话
Well, thanks for the start
我走了
I'm out of here
我从来没混杂着这么怪的两种感觉
I've never felt such a strange combination
一边遗憾  一边消化不良
of pity and indigestion
他在那
There he is
我们一直在等你
We've been waiting for you
你去哪了
Where have you been?
你还要害我们在这傻站多久
How long are you going to keep us standing here?
海绵宝宝
Well, Spongebob
你到底要目瞪口呆傻站着
are you just going to stand there
like a half-wit, mouth agape
还是把大家的餐都做好
or are you going to fill these people's orders?
别吵  章鱼哥
Pipe down, Squidward
大家样子都很生气
This crowd looks angry
不用让他们再等了
They're not going to wait any longer
我马上迅速就把大家想要的送上来
I think I better give them what they need and fast
最好是这样
I think so, too
不然老螃蟹会把我们俩都开除
or Krabs will fire both of us
我多想了下  让客人继续等吧
On second thought, keep them waiting
做不到  章鱼哥
No can do, Squidward
客人要的是娱乐
These people demand entertainment
娱什么
Enter what?
大家怎么样啊
How you doing, folks?
很饿
Hungry
那就不成问题  女士们细菌们
That's no problem, ladies and germs
因为海绵宝宝要来
'cause Spongebob is here
满足大家
to satisfy
都怪你要来这吃饭
Eating here was your idea
我管这首叫  条纹毛衣
I'd like to call this little number "Striped Sweater"
最适合穿条纹毛衣的时节
The best time to wear a striped sweater
是每分每秒
Is all the time
它的衣领翻得特别高
One with a collar, turtleneck
这种特别好
That's the kind
因为当你穿着
'Cause when you're wearing
我们饿坏了
We're starving
那件
That one
特别毛衣
special sweater
章鱼哥  客人都不满足
Squidward, this crowd is insatiable
那不然你就回厨房去
Then why don't you get back in the kitchen
拿点肉饼
and grab some patties
给大家想要的
and give them what they came here for
杂耍
Juggling
谢了  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squiddy
开什么玩笑
Is this some kind of joke?
客人想要一边杂耍一边听玩笑吗
They want juggling and jokes at the same time?
太难伺候了
Tough crowd
现在他又干什么了
Now what's he doing?
车在血库三里外抛锚的吸血鬼叫什么
What do you call a vampire
whose car breaks down three miles from a blood bank?
出租车
A cab
我们快没胃口了
We're losing our appetites
好  有个尼姑
Okay, there's a nun
宇航员  还有吹风机
an astronaut, and a hairdryer
我们要蟹黄堡
We want patties
我一次最多只能耍三块
Well, the most I can juggle is three
但表演不能停
But the show must go on
我的生涯结束了
My career is over
这么多年摸爬滚打
All those years clawing my way up
跨越前人  全都白搭了
All the people I've stepped on, wasted
终于啊
Finally
我们一直就在等这个
That's what we've been waiting for
大家好像很喜欢我把肉饼放烤架上
They seem to like it when I put this patty on the grill
这一幕多半还能抢救回来
I may be able to save this act yet
顺其自然  海绵宝宝
Roll with it, Spongebob
顺其自然
roll with it
还有不少呢
There's more where that came from, folks
喜欢吗
You like that?
我们一直都很想要
It's what we wanted all along
成功了  可是得怎么跟进
It's working, but how do I follow it up?
要当机立断  海绵宝宝
Think on your feet, Spongebob
走到这步全都是靠当机立断
That's what got you this far
面包
Buns
虽然事情难办
It's a stretch
但总有一刻必须挑战极限
but we all got to try to push the envelope sometime
大家觉得这个怎么样
Okay, folks, how do you like this?
开辟新天地了
I'm breaking new ground
来躁起来吧
Time to get edgy
我们要洋葱
We want onions
奶酪
Cheese
准备看压轴好戏了吗
Ready for the grand finale?
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patties
海绵宝宝  看来
Well, Spongebob, looks like
你总算发现自己的使命了
you finally found your calling
确实
I'll say
很高兴我能为这个放弃厨师工作
I'm so glad I gave up fry cooking for this
一角钱的故事
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
蟹堡王的打烊时间
Closing time at The Krusty Krab
51  52  53
51, 52, 53
29  30  31
29, 30, 31
一二三
One, two, three
蟹老板  能走了吗
Mr. Krabs, can we please go now?
我们某位更加忠诚的员工
Perhaps one of our more loyal workers
估计可以帮你讲明白员工守则
can enlighten you on company policy
蟹堡王员工守则第二修订版
The Krusty Krab Employee Manual
Second Revised Edition
第35页第19节3a款
page 35, section 19, clause 3a states
全体员工须留在蟹堡王
"All staff must remain on the premises
直至当天的收入全部清点完毕
until the day's receipts are fully accounted for"
可那样很过分
But that's not fair
第3b款
Clause 3b
业主留有过分对待员工的权利
"The proprietor reserves the right to be unfair"
真会答
Teacher's pet
数数看
Let's see
五  十
five, ten
25  蓝色
25, blue
苹果酱
applesauce
看来井然有序
Everything looks to be in order
除了
Except
哪去了
Where is it?
怎么了
What?
一毛钱
My dime
我特别的一毛钱
Me special dime
我赚的第一毛钱
The first dime I ever made
我一直放收银机最里面图吉利的
I always keep it at the back of the register for luck
我从来没见过
Well, I've never seen it
那你准备好
Are you prepared to say that
双手放在形意舞季刊上面发誓吗
with your hand on a stack of
Interpretive Dance Quarterlies?
舞蹈季刊
我当然
Of course I
你胡说八道什么
What are you saying?
我
Me?
我并没有针对哪个谁
I ain't saying nothing that would matter to anyone
除非那个谁愿意来测谎
who'd be willing to take a lie detector test
你话中有话
You're saying something
那可不至于
Heavens to Betsy, no
单纯只是我的幸运一毛钱不见了
It's just that me lucky dime's gone missing
刚好你整天都在负责收银
and you've been working the register all day
你是要让我背锅吗
Are you accusing me of something?
依我看  有三种可能
Well, the way I see it, there are three possibilities
第一种
One
是你偷的
you stole it
第二种
Two
是你偷的
you stole it
第三种
Or three
是你偷的
you stole it
我没偷你的宝贝一毛钱
I didn't take your precious dime
触手拿出来
Show me your tentacles
凭什么
What?
我要看到你吸盘没东西
I want to see empty suction cups
来来来
Here, here, here
看到没
See them?
你
You
不能那么整我
you can't do that to me
我是你老板
I'm your boss
再也不是了  蟹老板
Not anymore, Mr. Krabs
我辞职
I quit
不
No
我这就走
I'm out of here
章鱼哥  你犯下大错了
Squidward, you're making a big mistake
大错
Mistake?
我唯一犯下的大错
The only mistake I ever made
就是在蟹堡王浪费大好年华
was wasting my life at The Krusty Krab
可大家来蟹堡王都会快快乐乐
But a visit to The Krusty Krab makes everyone happy
什么能比微笑服务更棒呢
And what could be better than serving up smiles?
上西天什么的
Being dead or anything else
我都不知道这事让你反应这么强烈
I never knew you felt so strongly about this
你刚刚跑哪去了
Where have you been?
看来我也拦不住你了
Well, I guess I can't stop you
可是章鱼哥
But, Squidward
外面是个严寒的世界
it's a cold, cold world out there
幸福不是白送的
No one's going to serve you happiness
on a silver platter
免费试吃品
Free sample?
饼干
Cookies
能来一块吗
Can I have one?
总之  我想让你知道
Anyway, I just want you to know
如果碰上麻烦  就来找我
if you ever get in trouble, come find me
我会照顾你的
I'll take care of you
因为你和我
'Cause you and me?
我们就像兄弟
We're like brothers
只是更亲密
Only closer
海绵宝宝  我不需要你来帮忙
Spongebob, I don't need your help
我已经准备好释放潜力了
I am ready to unlock my potential
我能成为我想成为的角色
I can become anything I set my mind to
可以当橄榄球球员
I could be a football player
或者国王
or a king
或者太空人
or a spaceman
或者太空上打橄榄球的国王
Or a football playing king in space
还长了个胡子
with a mustache
对
Yeah
这倒是让我想起来了
You know, that reminds me
自打相识那天  我一直有话要跟你说
there's something I've been wanting to say to you
since the day we met
再见
Good-bye
等下次你见到我
Next time you see me
全城都会对我卑躬屈膝
this town will be eating out of the palm of my hand
赏点钱
Spare change?
赏点钱  大姐
Spare change, ma'am?
章鱼哥
Squidward?
章鱼哥  是你吗
Squidward, is that you?
我
I
是我  海绵宝宝
It's me, Spongebob
我们从前是同事
We used to work together
海绵宝宝
Spongebob?
没错
There you go
所以你这几天都住哪
So where you living these days?
请问是章鱼哥吗
Squidward Tentacles?
什么事
Yes?
在这签字
Sign here please
无处可去
Nowhere
好  那你近况如何
Great, and what have you been doing with yourself?
不对  我先猜猜
No, wait, let me guess
看得出来你一直都在留胡子
I see you've been working on that mustache
衣着破烂
The tattered clothes
臭气熏天
the awful smell
你是橄榄球球员
You're a football player
不对
No
太空人
A spaceman
不对
No
太空上打橄榄球的国王
A football playing king in space?
你还不明白吗
Don't you get it?
我是个失败者
I'm a loser
我没了工作  没了家
I've lost my job, my home
没了一切
everything
连画都没了吗
Even your paintings?
没人愿意买画  我就只能吃了
Nobody would take them, so I had to eat them
好啦
There, there
你可以来跟我住
you can come live with me
进去吧  章鱼哥
Here you go, Squidward
你就睡我床上
You sleep in my bed
好  我找到工作马上走
Okay, but just till I get a job
最多住个一两天
One day, two days tops
别见外  需要住多久就住多久
Nonsense, you stay as long as you need to
晚安  我的小天使
Good night, my little angel
早餐做好了
Breakfast is ready
你需要养精蓄锐
You'll need to build up your strength again
所以我就帮你做了大自助
so I laid out a big buffet for you
在床上吃吗
And in bed, too?
谢谢  海绵宝宝
Thanks, Spongebob
海绵宝宝  我
Spongebob, I
飞机来了
Here comes the plane
你真好
It's really nice of you
能在我需要的时候帮助我
to help me in my time of need
我尽量不拖累你
I'll try not to be a burden
不麻烦的
It's no trouble
还要我帮你做什么
Is there anything else I can do for you
胜利者
winner?
不用了  你已经
No, no, no, you've already
那个
well
针灸
滋养破碎的心灵可多事了
Nourishing a broken spirit is a lot of work
把我累坏了
I'm bushed
不过做好事还是让我很舒心
Still, it feels nice to do good
晚安  小蜗
Good night, Gary
海绵宝宝
Spongebob
能给我倒杯水吗
can I get a glass of water?
谢谢
Thank you
晚安
Good night
海绵宝宝  能给我再盖条毛毯吗
Spongebob, can I get some more blankets?
给你
Here you go
谢谢
Thank you
海绵宝宝  你忘记关灯了
Spongebob, you forgot to turn out the light
晚安
Good night
小蜗
Gary
章鱼哥才没有吃白食
Squidward is not a freeloader
他肯定不会占我便宜
And he would never take advantage of me
三周后
只是不容易重拾信心罢了
He's just having a hard time
getting his confidence back
很多月后
他马上就要有重大进展了
I'm sure he's close to a breakthrough
过了很久
老旁白已经等烦了
于是只好雇了个新旁白
我知道他还是没去找工作
I know he still isn't looking for work
不用你再强调
Don't rub it in
海绵宝宝  我的柠檬水呢
Spongebob, where's my lemonade?
来了  章鱼哥
Coming, Squidward
海绵宝宝
Spongebob
你怎么没穿制服
And why aren't you in uniform?
你早该来了
It's about time you got here
喝吧  陛下
Here you go, your majesty
这我不能喝
I can't drink that
为什么
Why not?
你瞎吗
Are you blind?
自己看
Just look at it
怎么了
What about it?
这柠檬里面有三颗籽
That lemon has three seeds in it
是奇数
That's an odd number
带奇数的我都吃不下
I can't eat anything odd numbered
好  那我挑出来
Fine, I'll just take it out
不行
No
它已经被坏柠檬污染了
It's already contaminated by the bad lemon
早就坏了
It won't work
家里有两样东西坏了
That's two things in this house that won't work
那就去修
Then go fix them
两样东西坏了
Two things that won't work
不工作
柠檬水我不要了
I've changed my mind
改喝汤
I want soup instead
好
Okay
别动
Don't move
喝吧
Here you go
是字母汤
It's alphabet soup
我特制的
I made it special
找工作
浓缩罐头汤
Condensed soup from a can
恶心
Disgusting
现在你倒是坏了我的胃口
Now you've ruined my appetite
给我拿点书报什么的看
Go fetch me something to read
行
Okay
这个看不看
How about this?
招聘启事
给我拿开
Get that away from me
我对印刷油墨过敏
You know I'm allergic to newsprint
你把报纸从我手上拍飞
You know, when you swatted that newspaper
out of my hands
让我想起来我有个朋友
it reminded me of something a friend of mine did
上班也这样过
at his job
四点了
4:00
给我演故事
Time for my stories
快啊
Hurry up
你懒懒散散的  节目还会照样放
they won't hold the show while you laze around
你要上哪去
Where you going?
去上班
To my job
你居然有工作
You have a job?
干嘛会没有
Why wouldn't I?
我又不是某些不为他人着想的懒鬼
I'm not some lazy, inconsiderate jerk
整天赖在床上
who lays in bed all day
那我可以上哪找到这种工作呢
Say, where can I get one of these jobs?
到处都可以
They're everywhere
绿色  还长六只触手的那就更好了
Especially if you're green and have six tentacles
谢了  我马上就去找工作
Thanks, I'm going to go look for one
这样就不用占我朋友便宜
so I can stop mooching off my friends
让他们回归正常生活
and they can get back to their lives
我又不看这部
This isn't my show
海绵宝宝  遥控器坏掉了
Spongebob, the remote control's broken
给我过来修
Get over here and fix it
我有更好的办法
I've got a better idea
不然打电话找专职工作的来修吧
Why don't I call someone whose job it is to fix it?
知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为要把工作做好
Because when I need a job done
就要找专职工作的来负责工作
I get someone with a job to do that job
你说的什么
What are you saying?
给儿童基金会捐款
Donate to the children's fund?
凭什么
Why?
儿童有替我干什么没
What have children ever done for me?
你想要回你的一毛钱吗
You want your dime back?
收下
Take it
现在章鱼哥能回来了吧
Now Squidward can come back, right?
不行
Wrong
这不是我的第一毛钱
That ain't my first dime
那就再多收点一毛钱
Then have some more dimes
我还有不少
I've got plenty of them
我的第一毛钱不能用价格来衡量
You can't put a price on me first dime
而我也不能原谅
And I can't forgive
那个偷我钱的毛贼章鱼哥
that thieving bilge rat Squidward for stealing it
听好了  你这个小气螃蟹
Listen you crustaceous cheapskate
章鱼哥一直借住我家  快把我逼疯了
Squidward's been living at my house driving me crazy
你却只因一毛破钱就不把他雇回来
And you're not going to hire him back
all because of a stupid dime?
那是什么
What's that?
我的第一毛钱
Me first dime
钱钱
Oh, dimey
我再也不会失去你了
I'll never lose you again
那居然是一毛钱
This is a dime?
我很早就在做生意了  小子
I've been in business a long time, boy
所以
So
章鱼哥没偷那一毛钱
if Squidward never stole the dime
就表示他能回来工作了对吧
he can come back to work, right?
没错  小子
Aye, lad
让我和一毛钱好好独处
Just let the dime and me have our privacy
章鱼哥先生  你能回来真好
Well, Mr. Squidward, it's good to have you back
能回来确实很好  老板
Well, it's kind of good to be back, sir
事情都过去了
It's all water under the bridge now
没错  老板
I agree, sir
毕竟嘛
After all
你肯定也不是故意要乱放我一毛钱的
I'm sure you didn't mean to misplace me dime
什么
What?
你在胡说八道什么
What are you saying?
很明显是你把一毛钱放我裤子里的
Well, it's obvious that you put the dime in me pants
一毛钱可不会平白无故飞裤子里
Dimes just don't fly into people's pants
你是要让我背锅吗
Are you accusing me of something?
依我看
Well, the way I see it
有三种可能
there are three possibilities
第一种
One
是你放我裤子里的
you put the dime in me pants
第二种
Two
是你放我裤子里的
you put the dime in me pants
第三种
Or three
是你放我裤子里的
you put the dime in me pants